here's a classic visual infinite sum
start with a unit square cut it into
four pieces and shade three of them
shading an area of 3/4s cut the
remaining 1/4 into four pieces and shade
three of them so that we've now shaded
an additional 3 over4 squar continue
repeating this process cutting the top
one quarter into four equal pieces and
shading three of them at each stage this
means we've shaded 3 over 4 to the end
of the total area of the square if we
continue this indefinitely Or imagine
the limiting process we see that in the
limit the entire Square diagram will be
shaded and therefore we've shaded an
area of one this means that 3 * the
infinite sum of the powers of 1/4 is one
one interpretation is that 0.3 repeating
in base 4 is 1 and another
interpretation is that the sum of the
infinite poers of 1/4 is
1/3